What is your profession?
What is your job?
Sir, we…
Helpers.
Company work…
Did you both come together?
Are you here together?
Helpers.
I'm so sorry.
-What's your name?
-Chaminda.
Chaminda?
Chaminda.
Passport?
Brother, I can't find our names
on any of these placards.
Look, they're taking many people
and verifying their names and documents.
Passport?
Brother, which flight did you arrive on?
No.
-What did he ask?
-No idea.
-What did you say?
-"No."
I said, "I don't know."
Go and ask them
if our names are on their list.
Me?
They won't understand if I ask them.
Hey, they are leaving!
Go! Hurry up!
-Have you come from Bombay?
-Sri Lanka.
Which company are you working for?
They are from Sri Lanka.
Allah!
Whom do we ask now?
If it's an office number,
there's no way you can reach them.
Today is Friday,
and it's a holiday here.
Do you have any other phone number?
A residence number or pager number?
Due to the anxiety of boarding the plane,
I forgot to ask about all that.
The phone is ringing,
but no one is answering.
It might be an office number.
This is so foolish.
We should have asked the agent in Bombay
for the contact number
of the person picking us up.
Well, fantastic timing.
You don't have to worry.
The Kafeel will come.
You have visas, right?
He must be stuck in traffic
because it's a holiday.
Brother…
I think everyone who came with us
has left. I can't see anyone here.
Would they have left
without recognizing us?
Brother, it's 8:30 p.m.
My mother must be getting really worried.
Shouldn't we inform them that
we've arrived here from Bombay?
It's late in the night.
But how?
The evening prayer just ended.
Oh! There's a time zone difference
between here and India, right?
Did you notice how happy Shashi was
when I gave him my watch?
Poor fellow.
He has been waiting for so long
in Bombay to come to the Middle East,
just like us.
Hakim!
I think he's our man.
It seems like he's looking for someone.
Shall we go and ask him?
Go and ask him in English.
No, I don't think that would work.
He's coming here.
Is your name Abdullah?
And you?
What is your name?
Tell him that we have come here
on Sreekumar sir's visa.
I'm asking for your name!
Can't you hear me?
Where have you come from?
Who is your Kafeel?
Don't you have any brains?
Oh, God!
Such a disaster!
What did he say?
All I understood was "Abdullah."
He was stinking, right?
Well, didn't you joke before
that attar and perfumes are made
from the sweat and urine of Arabs?
I wasn't joking.
The real Arabs are like that.
They bathe using water infused with attar.
This guy seems like a rugged Arab
who hasn't bathed in ages!
Anyway, the Kafeels are
still turning up, right?
What?
Kafeel.
That's the first Arab word
I learned after coming here.
What does it mean?
It means…
Boss.
Our man.
Our employer.
Sponsor.
Kafeel!
I wonder where our Kafeel is.
Give me your passport.
Give me your passport, too.
Brother, he's our Kafeel. Let's go.
Come on, let's hurry!
It's already late.
I don't understand what
these guys are saying.
Don't you want to go quickly?
Come on! Get inside!
Get in the vehicle! Come on!
What is this?
-Sir…
-Get inside, quick! Come on!
These guys are driving me crazy.
Sir, may I get some water to drink?
What are you murmuring?
Water.
Don't you understand?
Go and sit at the back. Go!
Get into the vehicle. Come on.
Don't waste time.
What are you doing? Not here!
Didn't I ask you to go there?
Go and sit at the back!
Go!
Brother!
Why is he shouting so much?
He wouldn't have
understood what we asked.
Well, we've come here as
company helpers, right?
And they are taking us in this vehicle?
Didn't you see?
Those Sri Lankans were taken in an AC bus.
You get in.
May God protect us.
I always wanted to come to Dubai--
Brother, look!
It's a tunnel.
Vehicles are passing above this tunnel.
Brother! It's even better
to stand and watch!
Come on!
It's really late, Hakim.
We haven't been able to contact
anyone back home yet.
Oh, I completely forgot about that!
We should stop somewhere
and make those calls.
-Kafeel!
-No!
Let's make those calls
once we get to our room.
Brother, it's already past 10:00 p.m.
My mother must be terrified.
Hey.
Kafeel!
I need to make a call home.
Could you please stop the vehicle?
Why are you blabbering?
Go! Go back!
The cops will catch you!
You can stop at a phone booth.
Can't you understand?
Go back and sit!
How do I make him understand?
-Brother!
-Yes!
Where are you taking them?
To the market?
-Wishing you well!
-Wishing you the best!
May God bless you!
Where are we?
Have we reached?
Abu Khaled!
Get down.
I asked you to get down.
This is your workplace.
Can't you hear me?
What's going on?
Get down.
No. You stay here.
You come with me.
-Hey, brother!
-Sir!
Sir!
We assumed our accommodation
would be in town.
We need to call our families.
-Phone call--
-You're blabbering too much!
Go! Go back to the vehicle!
Hakim, try to make
him understand somehow.
Isn't he asking me
to get back into the vehicle?
Don't you dare talk too much!
Go and get into the vehicle.
Don't be a pain in the neck! Go!
Kafeel, we are together…
Open your mouth and say something!
Hello!
Hello, Abu Khaled!
Why have you locked the gate?
Due to the threat of wild animals.
Listen, Abu Khaled.
Let this boy stay here.
-Brother…
-I'll contact you tomorrow.
Kiddo, whether it’s English or Hindi,
just convey it in a language
you’re familiar with.
There is no other way.
Go!
Sir, Kafeel…
we've come on the same company's visa.
Helpers.
We stay together.
Shut up! Go back!
Go back! Quick!
Kafeel, we are together.
One room…
You move away.
Come on! Take him!
-Hakim!
-Brother!
Let go of me!
-We have come together!
-Hey! Go back, I say!
-Go back, I say!
-Brother!
-Listen to me!
-Why are you hitting me?
Go back, I say!
-Brother!
-Be careful with him!
-Don't let go of him!
-Why are you hitting me?
-Where are you going?
-Come on now!
-We have come together!
-Brother!
-Where are you going? Come back!
Come on!
-Don't go!
-Stop the vehicle!
-Don't go, Brother!
-Hakim!
Don't go!
-Brother!
Praise be to Allah!
Get off.
Come on, get off.
Get down quickly.
Come on!
Get down quickly!
Where are you, Jaseer?
Are you sleeping?
No, Uncle. I'm not sleeping.
I'm here.
Yes, yes. I saw you.
Hello! How are you doing?
Doing great, by God's grace.
-Great.
-What's the latest news?
Latest news?
I've brought this Indian along.
Let him stay here.
We'll talk about
what to do with him tomorrow morning.
Okay, sir.
Go there. This is your workplace.
Where?
Karur Sreekumar said that
we'd be working in a company.
Go! Go with him!
Come on! Go and sleep
somewhere over there.
No.
Is he leaving?
I need to make a phone call.
You can use the telephone tomorrow.
Now go!
Goodbye! See you!
Bye! God willing!
-What? What are you saying?
-Oh, God! It's so cold!
This year, it's even colder.
Come!
Come on!
It's time to sleep!
Who is it?
Who are you?
What place is this?
Oh!
You're a Madrasi?
Why have you come here?
To work?
Hindi…
I'm a Tamilian.
Tamil?
Do you know
what kind of work is done here?
Can I get some water to drink?
Water.
Water?
Water is over there.
What was he even thinking?
Brother.
Where do I sleep?
What?
What are you saying?
Place to sleep?
-Where do I--
-Sleep anywhere you want.
Najeeb, that's enough!
Let's get back.
I need to scoop out six more
baskets of sand to meet the target.
The mason will give me an earful
if we wait to meet the target.
We have molding work today.
Get back on the boat.
What's with the new style?
Have you switched
from beedis to cigarettes?
Foreign cigarettes. Take one.
My brother-in-law bought
them from the Middle East.
-No, thanks.
-Take one, man!
Even without smoking,
I still can't stop coughing.
You've had this cough for a while now.
Go and see a doctor.
If it turns out to be pneumonia,
you'll be in trouble.
The doctor has asked me
to quit this job altogether.
Is that even possible?
Hey, Santhosh!
Didn't your brother-in-law from Karur
bring anything from the Middle East?
He has brought two visas.
Do you want to go abroad?
I'm just waiting for the visa from God.
I needn't spend money on that, right?
It's a free visa.
Hey, Santhosh!
Is that thing about the visa true?
Why? Do you want to go?
It will cost a lot of money, right?
It will cost at least 30,000 rupees.
But you can earn it back with
just two months' salary, right?
Thirty thousand rupees?
I'll have to sell my house.
Why do you have to sell it?
You can mortgage it, right?
It's only a matter of two months.
I've only studied up to the fifth grade.
What kind of job could I get?
You're not going to work
as a bureaucrat there!
Why do you need education to work
as a laborer? You have a passport, right?
You arrange the money, man!
I'll get the visa ready.
There he is.
The one in red.
I told you
my brother-in-law would be here.
As far as I can remember,
he has only missed this festival once.
Last year.
-During the Kuwait war.
-Okay.
Otherwise, no matter where he is in
the world, he'll be here for the festival.
Come on.
Brother!
Did you go to my house?
I knew that you would be here.
-This is Najeeb, the guy I told you about.
-Oh, yeah.
I'm Sreekumar.
People abroad know me
as Karur Sreekumar.
Shall we step aside and talk? Come.
Hey! Why are you late?
I cannot fly down like you, right?
Yeah, right!
Don't pull my leg!
I sold all my gold and other belongings
to arrange this somehow.
I know, man.
All Middle East expats
cross the sea like this.
Ask him what I had with me
when I got married to Kumuthavalli.
He was just a toddler running
around naked back then!
You are too much, brother!
I said that out of anxiety.
If I get cheated…
If you don't trust me,
you can have your money back.
I agreed only because he forced me.
There's a boy from Mayavaram
who's joining this company as a helper.
His father is in Dubai.
If I plan to deceive them,
do you think they'll be fooled?
No, brother!
That's not what I meant.
-My--
-Brother,
he has two brothers-in-law in Dubai.
To be honest, he married his wife
with the intention of settling down there.
Right?
What's the point in mentioning that now?
The anxiety of mortgaging my
house made me say that, brother.
Please don't misunderstand me.
Okay. You don't have to worry.
-Does it contain the full amount?
-Yes.
Pay the remaining 10,000 rupees
to the agent in Bombay.
-Only then will you get the visa. Got it?
-Okay.
Okay. Shall I make a move, then?
Hey, I had told Kumuthavalli
that you'd be coming home.
-Stop by there before you leave.
-Yes.
-Okay then! Carry on!
-Come.
We are taking the trouble
to make this unnecessarily, Sainu.
While he enjoys buffalo meat
and biryani there,
do you think he'll also eat your pickle?
Mom, the wealthy Arabs
eat camel meat there.
My brother Nasser brought some
when he visited once.
That reminds me!
Get him the phone numbers
of Nasser and Hussain.
They are his brothers-in-law, after all.
He can call them in case of an emergency.
Stop it, Mom!
I begged and pleaded many times
with my dear brothers
to arrange a visa for my husband.
Did they even bother?
Why do we need them now?
I'm waiting for Najeeb's first
money order to reach us!
I'm planning to purchase a copper vessel
from Kumbakonam and bring it home
so that my sister-in-law
can cook some biryani in it.
Mom, take this.
Make a delicious mutton curry
with added coconut shavings.
Don't get wet in the rain
and catch a fever before you leave.
Or do you want biryani, Sainu?
It's been a while since we had
Mom's biryani, right?
I'd like to have Mom's
mutton biryani before I leave.
What do you say?
You should have bought
a goat's head, too.
I would have made
some soup for her.
She needs to be eating properly
during this time.
I have arranged that.
You know Mammad, right?
I'll finish eating this
before boarding the plane.
I've asked Mammad to bring
a goat's head here every week
until her delivery.
After all, she's the wife
of a Middle East expat!
This is full of chili powder!
That's because you mocked me!
Am I really that desperate
to drink soup here?
The soup is not for you!
It's for my child!
Mom, did you hear that?
She thought the soup was for her!
Get out!
This is my tent!
-Let me lie down here.
-Get out!
It's really cold outside.
-Idiot! Don't you understand anything?
-Hey!
-I'll sleep here.
-Listen, you scoundrel!
-Please…
-If you repeat this, I'll break your legs!
I'll…
Bloody moron!
How dare he enter my tent!
Nuisance!
The day you stop giving milk,
you're dead meat.
Hey, Madrasi!
Come!
Come here.
I'm not from Madras.
I'm from Kumbakonam.
Tamil.
Najeeb.
What's your name, brother?
Your… name?
What is your name?
-My name?
-Yes.
I don't remember.
Take this milk to him inside.
Hindi… I don't…
No?
I don't understand Hindi.
Take… this milk… inside.
You scoundrel!
Who asked you to drink it?
-Didn't you ask me to drink it?
-Get lost!
Fool!
How do I make you understand?
This is not for you.
This is for the Kafeel.
The Arab! Over there!
Give it to him.
Go!
Of all people, the Kafeel
had to bring this Madrasi!
Useless!
Praise be to Allah!
Allah, protect me from all evil.
What is with you?
What are you doing over there?
Come on in!
Bring it here!
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you as well.
Do you know Arabic?
He knows Hindi.
Talk to him and learn
what has to be done here. Go.
Do you understand
what I'm saying? Do you?
I don't understand Arabic.
Go to him and learn how
to do the job. Quick!
What were you doing before this?
Tamil.
Tamil Nadu.
India…
I don't understand the Hindi language
you're blabbering.
Listen, don't give me a headache.
Watch that guy who speaks Hindi,
learn from him, and do your work.
-Go!
-Oh, my!
For God's sake, please save me.
I came here to work for a company.
I beg you!
Go way! What is this?
May you be damned!
I sold everything I had to pay for…
Damn you!
Sir, how do I even…
Let me leave.
I shall go back.
-Go! Go away!
-I shall go back!
Hey, Hindi! Come here.
Teach him how to do the job!
There's no point…
in crying.
Go!
Go away!
Oh, Allah!
Peace be upon you.
Company--
They took money from me for the visa,
promising a job in a company,
along with an AC room to stay
and good food.
He cheated me!
Karur Sreekumar…
Kafeel!
Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you as well.
-How are you doing?
-I hope you are doing good.
-I need to make a phone call.
-All good.
-Phone…
Go and keep that sack inside.
Don't trouble me.
I need to call my family.
Oh, God!
Don't you understand?
Take that sack inside.
Don't drive me crazy!
He will learn everything
in due course.
Seems quite difficult.
He doesn't understand anything.
-He will understand,
-Oh, God.
just like the other guy…
How do I make them understand?
Get up!
Take this.
What is this for?
I will leave.
Let me go back.
-Please let me--
-Listen to me. Wear it!
-I don't--
-You better listen to him!
Go and wear it!
I sold everything I had to come here.
I'm sure he won't understand
anything. Such a nuisance!
Please hear me out, sir.
I arranged the money to come here
by mortgaging my house.
He thinks that we can
understand his language!
Unbelievable.
Sir…
I paid 20,000 rupees to this person
who said he would give it to the Kafeel.
Karur Sreekumar.
Even the agent in Bombay
took 10,000 rupees from me.
-Papers?
-Yes.
Hey! What are you doing?
Don't tear it!
-That's mine…
-How dare you!
Keep an eye on him so he
doesn't cause trouble for us later.
Don't bother about that.
He's new here.
He'll learn everything soon.
Come on.
Let us begin in the name of Allah.
Come here!
Come here, man!
I asked you to come!
Come!
Friend, come here!
Come. Have some bread.
Bread! This is bread!
Look at him.
There's a saying
that bread can revive a person.
You are right, sir.
Come on. Come!
Sit down! Sit!
Take it.
Didn't I tell you that he must be hungry?
That's why he was so angry and finicky.
That's right.
Here you go.
Take one more piece.
Take it.
Be quick in learning
how to do the job, okay?
You heard me?
Drink some water.
Have it.
Drink it.
It's okay. Look.
Do this.
Do it.
Dip it like this…
and eat it like this.
Brother!
Why are you frightening my goats?
Where…
Road… Main road…
Where is it?
Road?
Yes.
Far away.
Far, far away.
Who knows how far.
I feel like I'm trapped
in the middle of the sea, Sainu.
How do I inform you about this?
TO MY DEAR SAINU…
Look at the sky.
Can't you see the moon
resembling a sliver of coconut?
Even if you can't call me,
just think of me when you see the moon…
wherever you are on this earth.
God has answered my prayers.
It must be the good fortune
of our child.
I'm not asking for much.
We need a room of our own,
a place to sit and talk like this.
Can we sneak into someone else's boat
like this once we have a child?
We need to fix the leaks in our kitchen.
And…
we should send our son to a good school.
That's all I need.
Have you decided that
we're going to have a son?
Don't you want a daughter?
I want a daughter as well.
Shouldn't we educate her
and raise her well?
Shouldn't we get her married?
You'll be an old man by then.
At most, four or five years.
Come back after that.
That's more than enough.
Is it?
Alright then.
Now, let me give my baby a kiss.
Nabeel.
Nabeel?
What if it's a girl?
Safiya.
Nabeel.
I think the train is about to arrive.
Son, keep your passport safe.
How many times
are you going to repeat the same thing?
God will be with you.
I will pray for you.
I will inform the local phone booth.
You can wait there.
Shall I go?
Mom, take care of Sainu.
Move.
Brother, please move.
This is the one.
-What's your seat number?
-Thirty-nine.
Easy. Careful.
Okay.
I…
You're leaving with a small bag.
But make sure to bring big suitcases
when you come back!
Sure.
It's over here.
Brother, it's okay even if you
don't bring anything.
But just don't forget about the visas.
-Okay.
-Come on. The train will leave now.
-Shall we leave, brother?
-Okay.
Happy journey, Najeeb!
He's leaving his house
for the first time.
I feel relieved because you are with him.
That's why we came here
from Mayavaram, to board the train.
-Take care of him.
-Okay.
Mom, don't be so anxious.
Dear.
Call me as soon as you arrive in Bombay.
I will call you.
Don't get drenched and catch a fever.
Mom…
take her to the doctor, okay?
You bloody dog!
We pay money to buy this water!
The water is intended for use
in our work here.
-I was just--
-Do you know the value of water here?
I was taking a dump!
If you touch it again,
I'll chop off your hands!
-If you take the water away, how will I--
-I pay money for it, and he's wasting it!
Water!
He pays good money to buy water!
Without water, how do I…
This is so bothersome!
Not water!
Use sand!
Damn it!
Brother!
Can you take me with you?
What?
When you head back,
can I ride with you in your vehicle?
What are you saying, brother?
I don't understand anything.
To the road. In your vehicle.
Can you take me with you?
What did this rascal tell you?
-I don't know.
-You don't know?
Come here.
Where are you going?
I know what he said.
Wasn't he asking you to help him escape?
No.
What were you telling him?
I didn't say anything.
I overheard you talking to him!
What were you blabbering to him?
I didn't tell him anything.
-Didn't you hear me?
-Why are you hitting me?
-I didn't say anything!
-What did you…
Let me go!
Let me go back!
I will go back!
You're fighting back?
Bloody scoundrel!
I'll teach you a lesson!
I'll show you!
What did he tell you?
I don't know.
The Kafeel was saying something.
Don't mess with him.
He can do anything.
You bloody scoundrel!
Bloody devil!
Do you think you can
fight back against me?
Sure! I'll kill you, you bloody dog!
Boss, he didn't tell me anything.
You shut up!
You don't need to get involved in this!
Why are you shouting at him?
He didn't tell me anything.
I didn't tell him anything.
You're grabbing my gun?
I'll pull the trigger
and blow your head off!
How dare you fight me, you dog?
I'll kill you and bury you in this desert.
Understood?
What are you staring at?
Can't you see the water overflowing?
Come on!
Idiots! You are all stupid!
Hey, girl!
Aren't you ashamed to bathe like this?
What's there to be ashamed of?
I'm bathing inside the bathroom.
We have such a beautiful river here.
You should be diving in there.
Hey, dear! What are you doing?
Someone might see!
I'm going to take you to the river today.
Dear, no!
Hey!
No! Najeeb, I feel shy!
-Let go of me, dear!
-Don't tremble!
-Mom, please ask him to leave me!
-What are you doing?
Where are you taking her?
Didn't you mention that
Dad carried you to the market?
But I was only 12 years old back then!
Mom!
Well, she's ten years older than that.
It's fine.
Let go of me! I'm scared!
Hey, Najeeb!
Hasn't it been nearly a year?
Is there no end to your craving even now?
Brother, my craving won't be satisfied
until her shyness disappears.
Hey! What are you saying?
I'm going to make you overcome
your fear of getting into the river.
Are you scared?
I'm scared!
Sainu…
Sainu!
Even after eating so much, you're still…
making these noises.
I think…
I'll die trying to feed you guys.
Brother…
Where have you been?
How long has it been…
How long has it been
since you came here?
"No one inside can go outside."
It's a very famous song!
No one inside can go outside
No one outside can come inside…
Hey, Hindi!
Get up!
Come on!
It's already late! Come on!
Milk the goats and bring me the milk.
Milk the goats and bring me the milk!
Come on!
Milk the goats and bring me the milk.
Come and milk the goats!
Hurry up!
Come on!
Quick! How can you still be sleeping
when the sun is already up?
Oh, God!
What is he saying?
Come here and milk the goats.
I…
I don't know how to milk the goats.
Milk them like this. Understood?
I…
How do I tell him that I don't…
Come on.
Come quickly.
I don't know… how to milk them.
-I don't know…
-Come on. Come quickly.
You idiot!
Don't try to milk it from the back.
You will get kicked!
Approach from the front
and gently befriend it.
I don't know how to do this job.
Where's that Hindi guy?
Listen.
Hold its legs, and keep them
in between your legs…
and then stroke it slowly.
Then try holding it.
And then, try milking it slowly.
-Understood?
-The…
The Hindi guy?
Isn't this his job?
What happened to him?
Stop blabbering and listen to me.
You also have other tasks to complete.
Don't cause trouble for me!
There are other jobs to do after this.
Go on!
Milk the goats.
There are things to do!
Hurry up!
This guy is the limit!
When is he going to learn all this?
Please…
Please don't get me beaten up.
I…
I don't know how to do this job.
Go!
Hey!
What are you doing, you idiot?
Are you fighting with the goats?
Get up!
Get up! Are you crazy?
Be thankful to your Gods
that you're not dead.
Water.
That's enough!
Go and take the goats back!
I won't give you another drop of water.
Get up! Take this.
Get up!
Come on! Get up!
Go on, bring the goats.
Oh, God.
I'm hurt.
I need to go to the hospital.
Stop blabbering
and take the goats back. Go!
I need to go to the hospital.
I asked you to take them back!
Hurry up!
This guy is so bothersome!
I can't do this.
Allah!
This is such a terrible situation.
Everyone has started buying machines.
But you're still the same.
You won't finish cutting this
even in one month.
This is easier than using a machine.
We've practiced this for a while now.
You are right, Jaseer.
We must change with the times.
If you take so much time to cut this,
there won't be any money left
to pay you when we sell it.
What are you doing?
Bring them quickly!
What's the purpose of making these sounds?
How many have you cut, Jaseer?
I'm doing it, sir.
It will be over now.
That's not enough.
Finish the rest quickly.
Don't you know
what the market is like right now?
You rascal!
What are you looking at in the mirror?
Admiring your beauty?!
Get back to work!
He's admiring his looks!
Idiot!
This beard…
How long has it been?
How many days has it been?
I can't remember anything.
How long…
I can't do this, Mom.
I'm exhausted, Mom.
I'm fed up.
I'm sick and tired.
God, I can't…
Why should I call on God?
Why should I pray to God?
If there were a God…
my fate wouldn't be like this.
Brother!
Brother…
Mom.
I need to go.
I must go back.
I don't care even if I die.
I must leave.
Stop there, you dog!
Go!
-You dog!
-Hey…
Stop there, you!
Where do you think you're trying
to escape to, you swine?
Where are you going?
Stay there, you swine!
Are you running away from me?
You dog!
What were you thinking?
I'll teach you a lesson, you dog!
You scoundrel!
I will kill you, you filthy animal!
How dare you run away from me?
Where were you trying to escape to?
Hey!
Who is that?
It's me.
It's me!
Brother…
Hakim!
Kiddo!
Brother…
I can't believe this!
Only your voice is the same.
You look so different.
Only your voice is the same!
Hakim…
I will die, brother!
I will… die here!
How long has it been?
How many years has it been?
I don't know anything.
I don't know anything!
Come on, brother.
Let's get out of here.
Let's escape from here. Come!
How?
Where to?
I tried so many times.
I tried for so many days!
It's been only a few days
since I came here.
I was made to work
at several places before that.
They tortured me!
Brother, that's my Kafeel.
I'm leaving.
I'm not afraid of dying now.
I could see you, right?
-Hakim…
-I was able to see you.
I'm leaving.
Go back, brother!
Don't let him spot you!
Brother!
What are you doing there?
-I'm taking a dump.
-Taking a dump?
Where are you taking a dump?
Listen!
Take the camels back to the Masara
before the sandstorm arrives.
I'm telling you, take the camels
back to the Masara before sunset.
Brother, I was severely beaten that day.
That's alright.
I'm happy that I was able to meet you.
I've only been working here
for a few days.
There's an African man
who works with me here.
He has worked here earlier as well.
He's very familiar with most
of the routes and locations here.
If he helps us, we can escape.
I feel like he has been sent to us
like Allah sent Prophet Moses.
Let's pray to the Almighty.
Hakim, come!
Quick!
Look! That's your friend's Masara.
It's okay.
Hakim!
What is it?
Nothing, brother.
-What happened?
-This is Khadiri.
Peace be upon you!
Ibrahim Khadiri.
How are you doing?
-Are you Hakim's friend?
-Yes.
Brother, Khadiri knows all the places
and routes here very well.
He's from Africa.
Escaping from the Kafeel
is quite difficult.
But the Kafeel's daughter's
wedding is coming up.
When the Kafeels go
for the wedding celebrations,
it might give us a window to escape.
May God help us.
-Hakim…
-Tell him.
Brother, our chief Kafeel's daughter's
wedding is coming up in a few days.
By God's grace, if they leave this place
that day, we can make our escape.
Didn't you understand
what I said, brother?
How?
So…
far away.
Can we do it?
Why are you speaking like this, brother?
If we can't escape, we'll die together.
Should we stay here and suffer?
-Hakim…
-I can't do this anymore.
I can't do this anymore.
Let's go.
Let's leave this place somehow.
Hey, don't cry.
Don't cry.
Come on, let's go.
See you!
God willing!
Brother, everything will be alright.
Pray to God.
Dear friends!
I greatly appreciate your presence.
May God bless you!
May God bless you all.
-You are most welcome.
-Thank you.
-I'm pleased to see you.
Welcome! Please come.
Hey, Hindi!
You're sitting here?
Take this.
Here, have some meat.
Eat it. It's for the special occasion
of my daughter's wedding.
God willing! On the wedding day,
we will serve you biryani.
Allah!
You are right!
What's with you?
Go and unload the goods from the vehicle.
I have to go to the wedding. Quick!
Alright.
Are you peeking at me from there?
That's an awesome speaker.
It has such great bass!
Unload it quickly.
He has to go to the wedding.
Oh, God!
I'll die in this heat.
Hey!
Hey! Don't worry.
You'll be getting
some of the wedding biryani, too.
-Sir!
-Yes!
I have unloaded the goods.
I'm leaving.
Come tomorrow. I'll get you
some biryani from the wedding feast.
Hey, you! Hindi!
Come on!
Here.
Take it.
This is your dinner for tonight.
I'll lock up the Masara and then
head to Kafeel's daughter's wedding.
If I'm held up, I won't return
until tomorrow morning.
Understood? Okay, bye.
Okay. May God protect you.
Don't scream.
I'll feed you.
Eat it.
Eat until your stomach explodes.
I'm leaving, my dear.
I won't be coming back.
I'm leaving.
Even if I have to face death, I'm leaving!
Someone else will come…
to take care of all of you.
Just like me.
I'm going back home.
Brother!
Come quickly!
Khadiri is getting impatient!
We need to hit the road
before it gets dark.
Brother, don't you
want to leave this place?
Brother!
Brother, you look completely different.
I never wore these clothes.
I was saving them to wear
when I finally return home.
Khadiri didn't even let me
change out of these dirty clothes.
He hurriedly dragged me
out of my workplace
as soon as the Kafeel left.
Hurry up!
We need to hit the road before sunset!
SAINU
Don't take that bag, brother.
If people notice us leaving with bags,
they'll figure out that
we're trying to escape.
Don't take the bag!
People will figure out that
we're trying to escape!
Come quickly!
Khadiri is also asking you
not to bring your bag.
Why do you need this bag?
Leave it here.
I haven't taken anything either.
How can I just abandon it?
Come fast!
Hurry up!
That's okay, brother.
Come on!
This is so tiresome.
Brother,
shall we go there
and drink some water?
Friend.
Can we go there
and drink some water?
No, no.
If we go there, they'll catch us.
-They might mistake us for thieves.
-No, no, no.
We want water.
Oh, God! How do I tell him
that I'm thirsty?
Water.
Wait here.
Don't move.
Sit. I'll bring water.
Thief! Thief! Thief!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Ibrahim!
Brother, come!
Come.
Hakim!
My bag!
My bag…
Brother, come!
Come quickly!
Come on!
Najeeb!
Is that a thief?
Shine the light on him.
I'm right behind him.
I can see him.
Stop! Stop him!
Shine the light on him.
Come quickly!
Hakim.
Oh, God.
Where are we going?
I can't see the road anywhere.
I think we've veered way off course.
Friend!
Ibrahim!
No road.
Are we on the right path?
Can't see any vehicle tracks here.
-Road?
-This is not the route.
We're just following the sun.
Come quickly.
We're simply heading westward,
following the sun.
Khadiri knows what he's doing.
We deviated from the route
while running. That's why.
Water!
Is the camel drinking water over there?
Thank God!
Come, brother!
Friend, look!
-No!
-Camel! Water!
Don't go there!
No water!
Heat! Desert heat!
Brother!
Brother, over there…
It's dead.
It's a dead camel!
It will take years to decompose.
We're running out of time. Let's go!
It must have died of thirst.
Hakim!
-What?
-Snake!
Don't move!
Brother! Are you okay?
The snakes were on my feet.
Oh, no!
There's a scratch.
Oh, God!
Did it bite him?
What happened?
It's nothing.
If the snake had bitten him,
he would have died immediately.
-What is he saying?
-It didn't bite you.
This is the medicine of the desert.
Medicine. Good.
Allah.
Praise be to God.
Glory be to God.
Friend.
Friend!
Get up!
-Get up.
-Have we reached the road?
You have rested enough.
Have we reached?
We'll reach today, God willing.
God sees.
Brother…
Brother, wake up.
We need to start walking
before it gets late.
My feet…
My feet!
Oh, God!
It's full of blisters
since you were walking barefoot.
My feet have swollen up.
Friend.
Wound.
Take a look.
You're wounded since
you were walking barefoot.
-Since you were walking barefoot…
-Let's tie this up.
This will help you walk.
Oh, God!
With these feet…
Oh, no!
Where are we…
going?
Why aren't we getting anywhere?
Satan is sending us around in circles.
Hakim!
Kiddo!
Hey! Open your eyes!
Hey!
Open your eyes! Open…
Hey, Hakim!
Friend, you're not tired!
Stand up!
Stay strong!
Shut up, bloody dog!
Don't utter another word!
If I had been back there, I could
have at least gotten some water.
Hakim.
-Kiddo.
-Water.
-Hakim!
-Road!
Road! We have reached!
Brother, it's the road.
Road!
Hakim!
Hakim…
You are fine, Hakim!
Hey, kiddo! Hakim!
Hey!
Hakim!
Kiddo.
Save him! Please do something!
Do something…
Save him!
Do something!
-Do something!
-Sorry.
-Please do something!
Save him.
Hakim!
Hakim! You are fine, kiddo!
Hey!
Hakim…
Hey, Hakim!
Hakim!
Najeeb!
Najeeb, come quickly!
Leave him!
-Hakim…
-Hurry up!
Hurry up!
-He's gone…
-Come! Quick!
Let's take him with us.
He'll be all alone here.
Hakim.
He will be all alone here.
Let's take him with us.
He'll be all alone here.
Hakim!
He will be all alone here.
Let go of me!
Let go of me! Hakim!
Hakim!
I can't see!
Hakim is gone…
Hakim!
Kiddo.
Praise be to God.
Najeeb, get up.
Najeeb!
Come on.
Get up!
Up, now!
Up!
Must walk.
We must walk till we die.
Najeeb.
Let me check your wound.
Allah!
Najeeb.
Lizard.
Look!
Look, Najeeb!
Najeeb!
Come!
Lizard! Water!
Najeeb!
Water!
Where?
Water? Where is it?
Where's the water?
Water!
Green!
Come!
Where is the water?
Where's the water?
Water…
Water.
Najeeb, water!
Green!
Praise the Lord!
Look!
Water!
Thank you, Lord Almighty.
Thank you for showing us the way.
Najeeb, don't run!
Najeeb!
Let go of me!
Water!
Najeeb!
Stop!
Water!
I need water!
-No!
-Water!
No!
-Don't drink water.
Not good. Not so fast.
-Water!
-Not good.
Little.
-Wait for me.
-I just want to drink some water.
I just want to drink some water
before I die.
Najeeb!
Fresh biscuit cover.
There are people nearby.
Hey, Najeeb!
Look!
Have we reached the road?
Tire mark! There!
-Road?
-Yes.
Road!
-Najeeb!
-Road!
Easy!
Road…
Hey!
Road?
Where is it?
Bringer of good
Your words are my guiding stars
Without you, I'm lost
Fading into afar
Shed some light on me
Where you are
Bringer of good
Your words are my guiding stars
Without you, I'm lost
Fading into afar
Shed some light on me
Where you are
Ibrahim!
Allah!
Are you crazy?
Causing trouble on the road!
Oh, my God!
Move away!
God saved me!
Should I drop you off somewhere?
Take me… with you.
It's okay. Don't worry.
Get inside.
God will protect you.
Get in.
It's okay. Get inside.
Slowly.
Don't worry.
The dirt is not a problem.
I'll clean it later.
You relax.
Water…
In the name of God…
Here, drink it.
Oh, God!
Please show mercy on this man.
Praise be to God.
Come on, step out.
Slowly.
Don't worry.
Take care.
Yes, good.
Come on.
Come on. Slowly, slowly.
Wait. Stand up.
The door.
Slowly.
You will be good.
Goodbye.
God will be with you.
Move away from the car!
MALABAR HOTEL
Wherever people may endure
hardships in this world,
they finally end up with you.
What kind of magic is that, Guruanna?
That's not magic. It's God's plan.
He must not have seen water
for a long time.
Don't bathe him for too long,
or he might catch a fever.
Dry him off quickly.
Suresh!
You don't need to give him
a stylish haircut or anything.
Just shave all his hair off.
His hair is filled with sand.
If I shave it completely,
it will start to bleed.
Let him be able to hold
his head up straight first.
He has a fever.
Should we admit him to the hospital?
What are you saying?
How do we take him out when he
doesn't have any documents with him?
Do you know the male nurse, Balamurgan?
I've asked him to come here.
If he gets a tetanus shot and an IV drip,
he'll be able to hold his head straight.
We'll ask him where he's from after that.
-Found it!
-Wow! And then?
-What did you think of me?
-That's good. Did you speak to them?
Well, of course!
Then provide me with the phone number.
Don't waste money on small talk.
-Write it down.
-Kumar!
-Note down the phone number.
-It's 04312313117.
It's their neighbor's house.
Call them right away.
They are waiting.
-I'll call right away. Thanks.
-Okay, brother.
What is it?
It's been a while since I last saw you
at our association meetings.
Where do I have the time?
Out-passes are ready
for a couple of people.
I'm seeking a sponsor
to purchase tickets for them.
Anyway, I have to make a call.
Are you always listening to music?
Isn't it time for your shift?
Get going!
Your fever has gone down.
Sit up straight for a while.
I tried calling
all the phone numbers you gave me,
but I couldn't get through to any of them.
It's been three to four years, right?
The numbers might have changed.
But the address you gave me is correct.
I inquired there
and found your people as well.
Your family…
must be waiting for my call
at your neighbor's house now.
Hello?
-Hello?
-Yes.
Hello? Is this Najeeb's family?
Yes. I'll get her on the line.
I'll pass the phone to him.
Here you go. Talk.
Hello?
Dear?
-Dear…
-Hel…
I can't believe it!
Oh, God!
Where were you?
Dear…
It's our son, Nabeel.
What's your name?
Tell him your name.
Najeeb.
Najeeb Mohammed.
India.
-Hindi?
-Yes. Hindi.
-Salih.
-Yes, sir.
Take his thumbprint
and record his name in the register.
Okay.
Give me your hand. Here.
Come on.
Come.
-Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you as well.
-How are you?
-I'm doing good.
-I'm good. What is this?
-Check this.
Indian. Hindi.
He doesn't have a passport
or a residential permit.
Doesn't he have his own photo?
No, he doesn't.
What are you looking at?
Have you seen any of them?
In the name of God,
let us begin.
Listen carefully.
-Silence!
-Make way!
Make way! Line up! Come on!
-Come on!
Line up so that your sponsors
can identify you properly.
No one should talk.
Keep silent.
What are they shouting?
-Narayana, please keep quiet.
-They've lined us up as if
we're goods for sale in a market.
Narayana, don't you know what will happen
if your sponsor identifies you
before the out-pass is issued?
You rascal! Where were you?
Where did you go?
I've been looking for you for so long!
Where were you?
Enough! Take him with you!
He was supposed to go
back home tomorrow.
-He is done for!
-I didn't do anything! Let me go!
-Dear Lord!
-Make way! Step aside!
-Go back! Line up!
-Sir, let me go…
Go back! Line up!
Go back! Step aside!
Go back!
Go back! Line up!
Bloody son of a gun!
You think you can fool me?
-I'll show you what I can do!
-Don't take me back!
-I will teach you a lesson!
-Please don't take me back there!
-Don't--
-I'll show you what I can do!
I will teach you a lesson!
Don't hit me!
So, you got away?
If you were really under my sponsorship,
I'd have hauled you back to the Masara.
It's so hot in here.
Najeeb, he was not your actual sponsor.
If he was, he would've dragged
you back to the Masara now.
Your visa was sponsored by someone else,
but this man abducted you.
He was working under this Arab.
So unfortunate.
ALL THE LIVES WE'VE NEVER EXPERIENCED
ARE JUST TALL STORIES FOR US
The three months I spent in jail
felt longer than the three years
I spent in the desert.
Since I began to feel hopeful
about returning home,
I haven't slept at all.
It was a long wait for the out-pass.
At the airport,
amid the crowd awaiting expats
with large suitcases filled with perfumes,
tape recorders, and televisions,
my son and Sainu will be waiting for me.
All that remains for me to give them
is the time I have left in my life.
THIS IS NOT JUST NAJEEB'S STORY.
IT IS THE GRIEF OF MANY THOUSANDS
WHO HAVE LOST THEIR LIVES IN THE DESERT,
LEAVING THEIR COUNTRY AND HOME TO SURVIVE.